

→ +30-6970630050

johneliades@hotmail.com
Project Showcase
GitHub
LinkedIn

### SUMMARY

As a seasoned software developer with many years of experience, I am poised to bring my extensive skill set to real-world projects. My journey has honed my abilities in crafting efficient and innovative solutions. Eager to embrace new challenges, I am committed to contributing to the success of a company that places its trust in me. With a track record of delivering results, I look forward to making a meaningful impact through my dedication and expertise.

### **EDUCATION**

• University of Thessaly, Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering(B.Sc & M.Eng)

Thesis: Torrent client in Go programming language.

2016-2021 GPA: 8.0/10.0

#### Professional Experience

### • Private Programming Tutor

2019-Present

Self Employed

- ➤ Delivered personalized instructions, tailoring sessions to each student's unique learning style and designed hands-on coding projects that allowed them to apply theoretical knowledge in practical, real-world scenarios.
- ➤ Covered programming fundamentals, including concepts, syntax, algorithms, and problem-solving, to build a strong foundation.
- ➤ Offered mentorship extending beyond coding, sharing industry insights, best practices, and effective learning strategies.

# • IT Support Administrator

2022-2023

Mandatory Military Service

Kos

My duties included the development, administration, operation and maintenance of the IT systems of the 80th NGHC(National Guard Higher Command) headquarters, as well as the units and subunits of the formation. Specifically:

- ➤ Managed configuration, and maintenance of diverse applications on the army's intranet, ensuring seamless functionality and user experience.
- ➤ Oversaw the Windows Server and clients to guarantee optimal performance and troubleshoot issues while minimizing downtime.
- ➤ Supported and trained staff on how to take advantage of the corresponding information systems, as well as networks and applications.

#### Personal Projects

To explore each project in detail, please click on the project titles. You'll be directed to the respective project's github page for a deeper dive into my work.

#### • Asynxy: Asynchronous RCE middleware webapp

2019

Created a webapp for remote command execution to a set of slave nodes, who periodically request new commands, execute them locally and post results back to the application using an http rest api.

➤ Tools & technologies used: Node.js, Express, Javascript, HTML, CSS, Python, MongoDB, MariaDB

### • Windows Server 2019

2019

Automation of mass user creation on a Windows Server 2019 with group policy (GPO) restrictions on the clients adequate for use in a school environment.

➤ Tools & technologies used: Batch

# • Portfolio

2019

A responsive website used as a portfolio depicting my projects, events I have participated in, and the skills acquired in the process.

➤ Tools & technologies used: Javascript, HTML, CSS

# • File Explorer

2020

A file explorer that achieves cross-platform functionality in a visually appealing way.

➤ Tools & technologies used: Java, Swing

### • Code Crawler

2020

A crawler that finds the answer to any software-related question by searching for accepted answers in popular sites such as StackOverflow.

➤ Tools & technologies used: Python, Google API, BS4

 Portal 2020

A recreation of the teleportation mechanics of the popular game Portal.

➤ Tools & technologies used: UE5, C++, Blender

• Chess Analyzer 2022

A script that finds the on-screen chessboard, runs a custom made image classification Keras model to identify the pieces and then highlights the best move using the latest local version of Stockfish while also providing a lichess link for further GUI analysis.

➤ Tools & technologies used: Python, Keras, Stockfish API

### • Village Movies Crawler

2023

A script that uses the village cinemas reverse engineered WebTicketing API to retrieve a list of currently playing movies and the ticket availability and showtimes, and sorts them according to IMDB rating.

➤ Tools & technologies used: Python, WebTicketing API, BS4

### **EVENTS**

#### Panoptis - Military Cybersecurity exercise

2019

➤ Our team at University of Thessaly solved and reported on Data Exfiltration, and Social Network Communication Analysis episodes.

Volos

### • Deloitte Hacking Challenge - CTF Cybersecurity contest

2019

Finalist, finishing 23rd out of 175 participants (40 participants in the final round) after solving various Athensproblems including web exploitation, reverse engineering, scripting, steganography etc.

# • Google Hashcode 2020

2020

➤ Solved the challenge using a relatively efficient greedy algorithm.

Volos

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

• Languages: C, C++, C#, Java, JavaScript, Go, Python, Bash, Matlab, R

• Frameworks: Express, Flask

• Other: HTML, CSS, JSON, XML, LaTeX

• Databases: MySQL, PostGreSQL, MongoDB

• Experience with various pentesting and reconnaissance security tools.

### LANGUAGES

• Greek: Native language

• English: C2 level ECPE certificate of Michigan University.